



Jalan Mutiara 2/8, Tmn. Mutiara Indah, Malaysia

rajeshp2408@gmail.com



in

BP

+60-166632408



linkedin.com/in/rajeshp2408/ bold.pro/my/rajesh-prasad



RAJESH PRASAD

SUMMARY

International Experience, IT Professional with 20+Years of experience in the IT industry with knack for simultaneously managing resources and working as system/support/deployment engineer.

12+years of experience in Service Fulfillment, Order Management, Order Fulfillment, Workflow Management, Order Orchestration, Inventory Management, Order Activation, Service Assurance, Network Performance Management, Alarm Management, Trouble ticket Management, Problem Management, Fault Management, SLA Management, Security Management.

One of my career highlights including leveraging continuous improvement mindset to revamp our customer complaint process and reduce resolution within SLA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

DevOps Tools

- Configuration management
- Version Management
- System Monitoring
- ☐ Container Management
- □ Testing
- □ Continuous Integration
- → Virtual Infrastructure
- Puppet, Ansible, Playbook and Chef, Saltstack
- Git, Pycharm, Jira
- Nagios, Datadog, Zabbix, Cacti, Splunk, ElasticSearch, Grafana
- Rancher, Docker, Kubernetes,
- Selenium, Junit, Cypress, Python, Cucumber, Chimp Js, Circle Cl, Postman
- Jenkins, Bamboo, Gitlab
- AWS, GCP, Azure, VmWare

Open Source & Server Skills

- Linux Server
- Databases
- Windows Server
- Web Hosting
- Applications/ Protocols
- Libraries
- BI Tools
- Language
- Virtual Server

- RedHat, CentOS, SUSE, Debian/Ubuntu
- MySQL, MariaDB, PL/SQL, MongoDB, CouchDB, PostgreSQL, OracleDB
- Active Directory(AD), Active Role Server(ARS), MS SCCM
- Cpanel/WHM, WHMCS, DNS Server, WordPress
- SOAP, JSON, YAML, XML, LDAP, NFS, FTP, SNMP, SSL, HTTP, SAMBA, Restful API
- Node.js, ReactJs, AngularJs, ExpressJs, Mongoose, BeautifulSoup, Pandas, Numpy
- Tableau, SAP Business Objects, Pentaho Enterprise Edition, Informatica PowerCenter
- Python, PHP, Javascript, R Programming, Bash Shell
- VMWare/ Hyper V, VSphere, Citrix XenServer, XenApp and XenDesktop
- KVM/OpenStack
- Veeam Backup & Replication

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Orange Business(APAC) (Viaccess-Orca)

Senior Support / Deployment Engineer

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Feb. 2022 - Present

- Squid, Fortinet F5 Network configuration/ Load Balancer
- Experience with enterprise-scale data warehouse technologies (Oracle / MongoDb / Sql and None Sql DB)

- Ensure the deployment, installation and commissioning phase of our digital TV products
- Manage the integration phase of our OTT/IPTV software solutions in the operator environment
- Participate in planning, implementation, and growth of our infrastructure on Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Manage full application stacks from the OS through custom applications using Amazon cloud-based computing environments.
- Bridge the gap between technical needs in APAC and experts teams (architects, R&D,Engineering team) located in Europe
- Experience managing applications in AWS and familiarity with core services including EC2, S3, ECR, RDS, etc.
- Running API testing using cucumber, python and javascript.
- Work closely with our architect and engineers to design networks, systems, and storage environments that effectively reflect business needs, security requirements, and service level requirements
- Manage a continuous integration/continuous deployment methodology for our server-based technologies
- Deploy and maintain PaaS & SaaS enterprise applications for development, QA, staging, and production environments hosted on cloud infrastructure.
- Understanding of a multitude of resources and services such as containers, virtual machines, storage, firewalls, network security groups, web application firewalls, vnets, log analytics, sentinel, monitoring, alerting, metrics, Data Factory, Databricks, Active Directory, Data Catalog, Web Apps, Functions, Application Service Environments, Key Vaults, Backups.
- Experience working with deployment and orchestration technologies (i.e., Virtualization (VMWare), Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Airflow, Anthos, Rancher, Helm etc.) on linux platform.
- Managing Infrastructure as Code using Ansible, playbook creation/deployment.
- Data oriented mindset, good knowledge of data-architecture and data-infrastructure.
- Linux, Web Technologies (application and HTTP Servers), ELK (Elastic Search / Logstash / Kibana), Grafana, Fluent Bit, Scripting (bash, perl, python)
- Knowledge with Video transcoding, packaging, delivery networks & DRM advantage

PCCW Solutions Malaysia Sdn Bhd (APAC)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Service Support Assurance- OSS Engineer

Oct, 2019 - Feb, 2022

- Design, develop and use Operations Policies for smooth operation of OSS Service Assurance Services, Business Process using Framework (eTOM).
- Create and maintain end-to-end architecture artifacts including but not limited to, High Level design, interface design document, process design document, sequence diagrams, data flow diagrams and data models across the OSS ecosystem
- Managing customer relationships spans an enterprise from marketing to ordering to billing to after-service support and follow-on sales.
- Regularly Meet with Operations teams to understand their concerns and develop action plans and strategy to address them.
- Planning OSS Service Assurance function's roadmap and strategy as per the prevailing Telecom technologies like Fixed line, IP based services, GSM, 3G etc.
- Strong hands on areas of OSS domain- Inventory, Provisioning/Activation, Order Management and Fault/Performance management etc.
- Experience with deployment of OSS and Network and Customer Provisioning, Operations, and Diagnostics systems through the delivery lifecycle from initial design to full operationalization
- An excellent knowledge of operator's fulfillment & assurance processes and link to operator's end-to-end business processes
- Solid experience in as-is/to-be architecture planning, solution scoping and design in OSS domain
- Interface with IT to ensure required OSS/BSS integration points are identified and addressed in a timely and effective manner.
- Experience in designing or implementing integration projects with various network management and/or Trouble Ticketing tools over standard interfaces (SNMP/ CORBA / XML/ SOAP, etc)

Adstream Asia OnTime (M) Sdn Bhd (APAC)

Technical Support Expert- Level 2

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Dec, 2018 - Oct, 2019

- Strong understanding of TCP/IP, routing protocols, Firewall, L2/L3 switches.
- Experience with security products -firewalls, IDS/IPS, VPN, virus scanning.
- Working knowledge in DNS, DHCP,OSI Model, and TCP/IP protocols and applications Active Directory, Domain registration and administration
- Hands-on implementation experience with Amazon Web Services (like EC2, S3, EBS, ELB, RDS, IAM, Route53, Cloudfront, Elasticache, AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, Amazon ECS, Amazon DynamoDB, AWS CodeStar, AWS CodePipeline, AWS CodeCommit, AWS CodeBuild, AWS CodeDeploy, Amazon Kinesis etc.)
- Familiarity with supporting deployment and development/Scripting languages such as PowerShell ,Bash, PHP,
 Python and Node.is application
- Familiarity with use of common Node.js modules, including Express and Cradle
- Good experience in developing web applications implementing Model View Control architecture using Django, Flask, Tornado, Pyramid Python web application frameworks.
- Experienced in working with various Python Integrated Development Environments like Net Beans, PyCharm, PyScripter, Spyder, PyStudio, PyDev and Sublime Text.
- Strong expertise in development of web based applications using Python, Django, HTML, XML, Angular JS, NodeJS, CSS, DHTML, JavaScript, JSON and JQuery.
- Experience in project deployment using Heroku/Jenkins and using web services like Confidential Web Services (AWS) EC2, AWS S3, Lambda, RDS (MySQL).
- Front-end: Backbone.js, Ember.js, CoffeeScript and ES6, CSS Bootstrap.
- **Technologies:** Distributed Systems, Databases, High Availability Systems, Machine Learning, Streaming Systems Networking concepts, Web servers, Apache & IIS
- Understanding and working with non-relational databases such as CouchDB and MongoDB
- Working on Relational Database servers such as Oracle 19c, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQL and SQL queries

BT System (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd (APAC)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Senior Support/System Engineer

Jun, 2017 - Dec, 2018

Key Technological skills:- Provisioning, Mediation, Billing, and Rating & Charging Metadata Management, Master Data Management Oracle BRM, Saas, One Seibel, SI- Single Interface, ESB, Agile Integration Broker, KCIM, Single Interface. Data Driven Solutions Agile methodology

Skills: Amazon Web Services (AWS) · Kubernetes · Terraform · Postman API · Logstash · MongoDB · Python (Programming Language) · Application Support · Ansible · Docker Products · Enterprise Systems · Analytical Skills

Aptilo Networks Sdn Bhd (APAC)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Senior Support / Delivery Engineer

Feb, 2014 - Jun, 2017

HOMT Infrastructures, Spain (International)

Luanda, Angola

System Engineer(BOSS Platform) (On Contract)

Aug, 2012 - Feb, 2014

Project: MSN Phase -2 for Angola Telecom (Wimax, PSTN/ADSL, CDMA)

Openet Telecom Malaysia Sdn Bhd (APAC)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Operations / Testing Engineer

Jun, 2011 - Aug, 2012

Alcatel-Lucent, Fr S.A (International)

IT System Engineer (Test/Comm/Network Admin) (On Contract)

Project: MSN Phase -1 for Angola Telecom (Wimax, PSTN/ADSL, CDMA)

Luanda, Angola

Jun, 2009 - May, 2011

UT Starcom India Telecom Pvt. Ltd.

GSSI Engineer

Gurugram, India Jul, 2008 - Jun, 2009

Kolkata, India

IOL Broadband Ltd. Mumbai, India

System Engineer May, 2007 - Jul, 2008

Inventum Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Noida, India

Tech Support- Layer 2 Dec, 2006 - May, 2007

Microsence India Pvt. Ltd. Kolkata, India

Customer Support Engineer (On Contract) Sep, 2006 - Dec, 2006

Bharti BT Internet Ltd (Formerly MantraOnline.com)

Customer Care Officer (On Contract)

Jan, 2001 - Jan, 2002

EDUCATION

IGNOU SOC&IS DELHI, INDIA

Bachelor Of Computer Applications Jun, 2006

CERTIFICATION

•	Certified SAFe® 5 Agilist	Dec, 2022
•	Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python (V2+)	Jun, 2020
•	MongoDB -M103: Basic Cluster Administration	Sep, 2019
•	MongoDB -M220P: MongoDB for Python Developers	Sep, 2019
•	MongoDB-M001: MongoDB Basics	Aug, 2019
•	MIT 6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python	Aug, 2018
	Credential ID 23fbe77018124839bb8de06b81557c2f	
•	Palo Alto Networks-ACE PAN OS 8.1version	Jun, 2018
•	SoloLearn - HTML5, Credential ID 1014-8365311	May, 2018
•	SoloLearn -Python 3, Credential ID 1073-8365311	Feb, 2018
•	SCSA - Sun Certified System Administrator (Solaris 10), Candidate ID: SR5459580	April, 2009
•	CCNA - Cisco Certified Network Associate (640-801), Cisco ID: CSCO11057874	May, 2006

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth :24th Aug, 1980

Hobbies :Tech Savvy, Listening Music, Reading, Travelling, Pythonista

Language :English, Hindi, Malay

REFERENCE

References and Supporting Documentation Furnished Upon Request

Place :Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.

Date :09/Jun/2024 - RAJESH PRASAD